Guide to the Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories
1920-1980
OH.002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
20.0 linear feet Approximately 390 cassettes
The Tamiment Library at New York University established the Oral History of the American Left in 1976 in order to collect and preserve the memories of veteran activists. These interviews describe seven decades of Left politics from the 1910s through the 1970s. They document the full spectrum of left politics in the twentieth century: Socialism, Communism, Anarchism, Trotskyism, and the New Left. There are interviews with both leaders and rank-and-file activists.
Tamiment Library.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions when release forms are indicated.
Historical/Biographical Note
New York University’s Tamiment Library established the Oral History of the American Left (OHAL) in 1976. The purpose of this project was to expand the archive of American labor and radicalism through the creation of “living documents” by recording the memories of veteran activists. The idea, according to Project Director Paul Buhle, was “to create an archive of recorded reminiscences by participants in trade union struggles, political organizations, and grass-roots political and cultural activity.” The archive is intended to preserve the identity and legacy of the Left in the United States and to not overlook any of the diverse cultures involved in the movement or undervalue past periods of conflict and oppression.
Complementing the above goals, Buhle was motivated to use the growing practice of oral history to shed light on and “capture a collective understanding of the little understood 1919-1929 decade.” Additionally, he sought to add substance to the emergent “new social history” by uncovering previously ignored perspectives through the stories of his subjects. Buhle believed these untold stories, such as about the roles of women and midlevel activists, would add depth and complexity to traditional research methods and challenge our understanding of social movements.
Paul Buhle has been the director of the project since its founding in 1976. The staff included Roger Keeran who was co-director in the early years and Jon Bloom who joined the project in 1977 to work as an interviewer, coordinator, and fundraiser. Additional interviewers included Ruth F. Prago, Bea Lemisch, Amelia Green and several NYU students.
Interviewing began with a series of small grants provided by the Rabinowitz and Bronson Cutting Foundations. The New Jersey Historical Commission provided funding in 1978 to support interviews on radicalism in New Jersey between 1930 and 1960. Later, Ruth F. Prago developed the idea to start a radio series based on interviews held for the OHAL collection. Together with Pacifica Radio the project received a one-year grant from the New York State Council for the Humanities to conduct interviews with twenty-five women about radicalism during the 1930s. Radio producers used these interviews to create the radio series “Grandma was an Activist,” first broadcast in 1983. OHAL received major funding in 1982–1983 from the National Endowment for the Humanities. This support enabled Paul Buhle to build a comprehensive collection of oral histories regarding ethnic-immigrant radicalism, its press and fraternal organizations. The NEH grant also enabled OHAL to collect hundreds of hours of interviews made by filmmakers on American anarchism, the Hollywood blacklist, the Communist Party, the Columbia University student strike of 1968, and other subjects.
The project also produced seven issues of a newsletter, and the transcript of a two-day conference co-sponsored by OHAL and the Tamiment Library on the occasion of the opening of the Max Shactman Papers in 1983.
Scope and Content Note
Series I: OHAL Main Collection
The tapes and transcripts in the Oral History of the American Left Series I collection came from a variety of sources. Most of the interviews were done by Jon Bloom, Paul Buhle, Bea Lemisch, and Ruth F. Prago. They cover many subjects including: immigrant/ethnic radicalism, labor, women's history, radical newspapers, fraternal organizations, and student radicalism between 1910 and 1980. The earliest interviews were done with men and women who could recall the 1910s–1920s. Later interviews focused on the effects of the Russian Revolution on the Left in the United States, the formation of social and cultural institutions by the "New Immigrant" groups, the history of Socialism and Anarchism, and the troubled early years of American Communism. In addition, notable efforts were made to interview rank and file or middle-level leadership activists, to focus on "radical women" and to focus on the labor movement, specifically the needle trades unions and the early years of the Congress of Industrial Organizations. For the most part, these interviewees did not leave behind written records so their oral histories are the only available historical record.
The immigrant ethnic interviews might be the most unique element of the collection. OHAL interviewed representative figures from the Jewish, Finnish, Slovenian, Greek, Hungarian, Polish, Italian, Ukrainian, Lithuanian, Japanese, Scandinavian, and Spanish Left. A handful of tapes recall the African American experience. The collection includes several interviews with participants of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, the US component of the International Brigades which fought in the Spanish Civil War, and covers activities related to the group. There are other interviews documenting the long tenure of Jasper McLevy, Socialist Party Mayor of Bridgeport, Connecticut from 1933-1957.
Ninety-five percent of these interviews are on cassette tapes with accompanying indexes. The rest are transcripts without tapes. The collection is currently being digitized and approximately half of the interviews are available on CD. In the near future, the entire collection will be available on CD. In addition, we are having numerous interviews be transcribed. We are aiming for half of the collection to have electronic and paper transcripts by mid 2011. Information about format is noted in the inventory.
Notable individuals interviewed include: Herbert Aptheker, Rosalyn Fraad Baxandall, Daniel Berrigan, Abner Berry, James Boggs, George Breitman, Rose Chernin, Malcolm Cowley, Samuel Darcy, Solon De Leon, Hal Draper, Raya Dunayevskaya, Melech Epstein, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Hugo Gellert, Todd Gitlin, Martine Glaberman, Albert Glotzer, Itshe Goldberg, Louis Harap, Michael Harrington, Howard "Stretch" Johnson, Mary Kolehmainen, Meridel Le Sueur, A.B. Magil, Thomas McGrath, Ernest Rice McKinney, Clarence Norris, Paul Novik, Harvey O'Connor, Louise Patterson, George Rawick, Lester Rodney, Annette Rubinstein, Pete Seeger, Norman Thomas, Stan Weir, Myra Tanner Weiss.
Several group interviews and conferences were recorded pertaining to the following organizations: Catholic Worker Movement, International Labor Defense, Johnson-Forest Tendency, Matteotti Club, Medem Jewish Socialist Group, Socialist Party(US), Southern Negro Youth Congress, Workers Party (1940-1949).
Series II: Fred Zimring/Barrows Dunham Collection This series contains interviews conducted by Dr. Zimring for his doctoral dissertation “McCarthyism, the Cold War and Temple University: the Dismissal of Professor Barrows Dunham from Temple.” He interviewed numerous individuals about the 1953 case including Professor Dunham, his friends and colleagues, and Temple University faculty and administrators.
Series III: David Leviatin/Reynolds Hill Collection Interviews in this series are with members of the Reynolds Hill Colony, originally called “Followers of the Trail,” in upstate New York. The group was founded by eastern European immigrant Jewish garment workers and included their own hiking camp for physical exercises and political discussions. Permission to use these interviews must be granted by the interviewer. Please contact the Tamiment Library for more information.
Series IV: Filmmakers’ tapes This series contains interviews conducted for documentary films on the history of American radicalism. They cover a range of subjects such as American anarchism, American Communism, the Hollywood Blacklist and the 1968 Columbia University student strike. Examples of films included in the collection are The Salt of the Earth. Interviews are listed under the title of each film for which they were produced and they are a mix of tapes and transcriptions. This series contains some restricted material where permission of the filmmaker is required.
Series V: Tamiment Institute Tapes This series contains recordings of meetings, speeches, and interviews held during the 1950s and the 1960s.
Series VI: Aleine Austin/Monthly Review and Highlander Folk School tapes These are interviews conducted by Professor Austin on the history of Monthly Review magazine, founded in 1949, and the history of Highlander Folk School, founded in 1933.
Series VII: Restricted Tapes These interviews are closed at the interviewees’ request for a specified period of time.
Arrangement
Alphabetical by name.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
Container list
American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born.; Baxandall, Rosalyn Fraad, 1939- -- |v Interviews; Berrigan, Daniel--Interviews.; Berry, Abner--Interviews.; Bloom, Jonathan; Boggs, James--Interviews.; Breitman, George -- |v Interviews; Buhle, Paul, 1944-; Chernin, Rose--Interviews.; Communist Party of the United States of America. -- |v Interviews; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989; Darcy, Samuel, 1905-; De Leon, Solon, 1883-; Draper, Hal -- |v Interviews; Dunayevskaya, Raya -- |v Interviews; Epstein, Melech--Interviews.; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence--Interviews.; Foner, Henry -- |v Interviews; Foner, Moe, 1915- -- |v Interviews; Gellert, Hugo, 1892-1985. -- |v Interviews; Gitlin, Todd--Interviews.; Glaberman, Martin--Interviews.; Glotzer, Albert, 1908-1999. -- |v Interviews; Goldberg, Itshe--Interviews.; Harap, Louis -- |v Interviews; Harrington, Michael, 1928-1989 -- |v Interviews; Industrial Workers of the World. -- |v Interviews; International Labor Defense. -- |v Interviews; James, C. L. R. (Cyril Lionel Robert), 1901-1989. -- |v Interviews; Johnson, Howard, 1915- --Interviews.; Johnson-Forest Tendency.; Kolehmainen, Mary--Interviews.; Le Sueur, Meridel -- |v Interviews; Lemisch, Bea.; Magil, A. B. (Abraham Bernard), 1905- -- |v Interviews; Matteotti Club.; McGrath, Thomas, 1916-1990. -- |v Interviews; McKinney, Ernest Rice, 1886-1984. -- |v Interviews; McLevy, Jasper. -- |v Interviews; Nelson, Steve, 1903- -- |v Interviews; Noṿiḳ, P., 1891-; O'Connor, Harvey, 1897-1987. -- |v Interviews; Patterson, Louise Thompson, 1901-1999; Prago, Ruth.; Rawick, George P., 1929-; Rodney, Lester, 1911- -- |v Interviews; Rubinstein, Annette T. (Annette Teta), 1910-2007. -- |v Interviews; Seeger, Pete, 1919-; Socialist Party (U.S.). -- |v Interviews; Socialist Workers Party. -- |v Interviews; Southern Negro Youth Congress. -- |v Interviews; Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.). -- |v Interviews; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968 -- |v Interviews; Trade Union Unity League (U.S.).; Weir, Stan -- |v Interviews; Weiss, Myra Tanner -- |v Interviews; Workers Party (1940-1949) -- |v Interviews; Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring. -- |v Interviews; Young Communist League of the U.S.; African American radicals |v Interviews.; Anarchism |z United States.; Anarchists |z United States |v Interviews.; Communism |z United States; Communists |z United States |v Interviews.; Finnish American radicals |v Interviews.; Hungarian American radicals |v Interviews.; Italian American radicals |v Interviews.; Jewish radicals |z United States |v Interviews.; Labor union members |z United States |v Interviews.; Labor unions |z United States; Labor |z United States.; Oral histories (document genres); Right and left (Political science); Slavic American radicals |v Interviews.; Socialism |z Connecticut |z Bridgeport (Conn.).; Socialism |z United States.; Socialists |z United States |v Interviews.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, American |v Interviews.; Student movements |z United States |v Interviews.; Trotskyists |z United States |v Interviews.; Women employees |z United States |v Interviews.; Women radicals |z United States |v Interviews.
- Minka Alesh, Oct 26, 1982 (Cd Access OH-02-159, Box 1, Cd Alesh 1, Cassette 1, Cd ohaloh020146p1 / /ohaloh020146p2)
  Scope and Content Note
  SNPJ (Slovenian Benefit Society), 1910-present; Haberdashery Union, New York and Chicago, c. 1910-20; Women's activities in Chicago; SNPJ and Socialist Party, 1910s-1920s.
  Interview by Paul Buhle.
- Ben Alexrod, Oct 4, 1979 (Cassette 391)
  General Note
  no access cassette / master only
- Jose Alvarez, Mar 15, 1983 (Cd Access OH-02-160, OH-02-161, Box 1, Cd Alvarez 1-2, Cassette 2, Cassette 2 A-B, Cd ohaloh020147b1p1 / ohaloh020147b1p2, Cd ohaloh020148b1p3)
  General note
  Transcript, Box 1 and index available
  Origins of Spanish language Communist movement in Ybor City, Florida, 1920s-1930s; community support of Communists and relation to surrounding communities, 1930s-40s; immigration from Spain, work in tobacco factories and activities of unions, 1920s-40s; Red Scare decimation of Ybor City Left, 1950s; meeting with Fidel Castro before Cuban Revolution, 1950s.
- Freda Hogan Ameringer, undated (Box 1, Cd Ameringer 1-2, Cassette 362 A, Cassette 362, Cd ohaloh020153p1 / ohaloh020153p2, Cd Access OH-02-167, OH-02-168)
  no access cassettes available / master only
- Freda Hogan Ameringer, Dec 11, 1977 (Cassette 362, Box 1, Cassette 362 B, Cd ohaloh020154p1 / ohaloh020154p2, Cd Ameringer 3-4, Cd Access OH-02-169, OH-02-170)
- Freda Hogan Ameringer, Jul 24, 1981 (Cd Access OH-02-171, OH-02-171, Cd OH-02-173, Cd ohaloh020155b1p1 / ohaloh020155b1p2, Cd ohaloh020155b1p3 /ohaloh020155b1p4, Cd ohaloh020156b1p6, Box 1)
  Interview by Jim Green.
- Vicky Amter, Feb 19, 1978 (Box 1, Cd Amter 1-2, Cd ohaloh020149p1 / ohaloh020149p2, Cassette 3, Cassette Access OH-02-162, OH-02-163)
  Communist Party, lower east side, N.Y., 1940s-1960s; conflicts with her father, a Socialist; experiences as Local 65 shop steward; Jefferson School; harassment and isolation of CP in the 1950s; reactions to emergence of the New Left.
  Interview by Jon Bloom.
- Herbert Aptheker Description: College radicalism in 1930s; Communist Party, 1976 (Cassette No Tapes)
  Transcript available, Box 1
  no tape
- Harry Aronek, Oct 25, 1978 (Cassette 4, Cd OH-02-164, OH-02-165, Box 1, Cd Aronek 1-2, Cd ohaloh020150b1p1 / ohaloh020150b1p2, Cd ohaloh020151b1p3, Cassette 4 A-B)
  Immigration; political and cultural activities in New York Jewish community, 1930s-1950s.
- Sam Ashare, Mar 30, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Ashare 1, Cassette 5, Cd Access OH-02-166, Cd ohaloh020152p1 / ohaloh020152p2)
  Interview by Dan Georgakas.
- Jacob Aspitz, Apr 7, 1980 (Cd Access OH-02-174, OH-02-175, Cd ohaloh020157b1p1 / ohaloh020157b1p2, Cd ohaloh020158b1p3 / ohaloh020158b1p4, Cassette 6, Box 1, Cassette 6 A-B)
  Los Angeles Jewish Left since 1930s; rise of anti-Nazi "front" across Jewish coimrunity and Communists' participation in it; isolation of Jewish Left during Cold War; literary interests and old age around Yiddishe Kultur Farband.
- Stanley Banach, Apr 11, 1984 (Box 1, Cassette A-B, Cd Access OH-02-095, OH-02-096, Cd ohaloh0200089b1p1 / ohaloh0200089b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200090b1p3 / ohaloh0200090b1p4, Cd Banach 1-2, Cassette 7)
  Neighborhood background in Providence, 1950s; Army life in Vietnam and in Germany, radical influences; union activity at Electric Boat/Quonset Point, Rhode Island, organizing drive; union activity at Brown & Sharpe before and during 1982 strike; political philosophy and aspirations.
- Eugene Barnett Description: Industrial Workers of the World, lumberwork; West Virginia coal miners, repression in Centralia, PA. c. 1910a, 1940 - 1946 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Walter Barry, Oct 12, 1980 - Feb 4, 1980 (Box 1, Cd Barry 1-3, Cd Access OH-02-176, OH-02-177, OH-02-178, Cassette 9 A-C, Cd ohaloh020159b1p1 / ohaloh020159b1p2, Cd ohaloh020160b1p3 / ohaloh020160b1p4, Cd ohaloh020161b1p5, Cassette 9)
  Boyhood and first labor experience in Endicott, N.Y.; Trade Union Unity League and United Electrical Workers District 4, Westinghouse Elevator plant, Jersey City, N.J., 1930s-50s.
  Inby Ruth F. Prago. Background
  Index available
  tape#: 3 U2A
- Irving Barshop, Oct 12, 1973 (Cassette 334)
- Rosalyn Baxandall, Nov 8, 1983 (Cassette 10, Box 1, Cd Baxandall 1)
  Background in New York Old Left; cultural awakening in Madison; political and cultural experiences in Madison, 1958-60s; beginnings of Madison's women's movement.
- Bertha Bazell, Mar 10, 1981 (Cassette 11, Cd ohaloh020162p1 / ohaloh020162p2, Box 1, Cd Bazell 1, Cd Access OH-02-179)
  Born 1896; immigrant Jewish background; Workman's Circle; Communist Party, 1930s-50s in Coney Island, N.Y.; later Fall River, Mass.; harassment by the F.B.I. in the 1950s.
  Interview by Bill Schecter.
- Ray Bell Description: Socialism/communism, Spain in WWII, Aug 2, 1985 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Fay Bennett, May 26, 1983 (Cassette 12, Cd ohaloh020163b1p1 / ohaloh020163b1p2, Cd ohaloh020164b1p3 / ohaloh020164b1p4, Cd Access OH-02-180, OH-02-181, Box 1, Cassette 12 A-B)
  College anti-war movement, 1930s; American Student Union; Keep America Out of War Congress, late 1930s; experience of conscientious objectors during World War II; postwar work with National Sharecroppers' Fund.
- Herman Benson, undated
  Transcript available, Box 1 release form
- Jack Bergen Description: Bridgeport in 1910s; Depression and Jasper McLevy; SP in Connecticut state politics, 1930s., 1967 (Item Transcript only)
  Transcript available, Box 1no tape
- John T. Bernard, Jun 25, 1977 (Cassette 14, Cd ohaloh020165b1p1 / ohaloh020165b1p2, Cd ohaloh020166b1p3 / ohaloh020166b1p4, Cd ohaloh020167b1p5 / ohaloh020167b1p6, Cd Access OH-02-183, OH-02-184, OH-02-185, OH-02-186, Box 1, Cd 1-5, Cassette 14 A-C)
  Mesaba Park Coop. Assn. tribute to John Bernard, U.S. representative 1936-38; speeches by former Minnesota Governor Elmer Benson and others about Bernard's record in Congress; response from Bernard; music.
- Daniel Berrigan Description: activities during the 1960s, Catonsville incident., Apr 1, 1970 (Cassette 15A-C)
- Abner Berry, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Cd Berry 1-6, Cd ohal02000b1p1 to ohaloh020002b1p4, Cd ohaloh020003p1 and ohaloh020003p2, Cd ohaloh020004p1 and ohal020004p2, Cassette 16, Cd ohaloh020005b1p1 to ohaloh020006b1p4, Cassette Berry A-F, Cd Access - OH-02-001 to OH-02-006)
  Communist Party in Harlem, 1930s; Ethiopia Defense Committee; Unemployed Councils; Richard Wright and CP cultural policies; CP branches and organizers in Harlem; opposition to CP in Harlem.
  Interview by Mark Naison.
- Steve Beumer, Jun 21, 1975 (Cd OH0-20-187, OH-02-188, Cassette 17, Cd ohaloh020168b1p1 / ohaloh020168b1p2, Cd ohaloh020169b1p3 / ohaloh020169b1p4, Cd ohaloh020170b1p5 / ohaloh020170b1p6, Box 1, Folder 17 A-C, Cd Beumer 1-4)
  Family background in Indiana and political activities there and in Detroit, late 1960s-1970s; Socialist Workers Party; experiences as bus driver and union activist in Detroit.
  Interview by Claudia Hommel.
- Martin Birnbaum Description: New Yorker Volkszeitung, Moshe Nadir; Yiddish literary community, Proletpen; c. 1920s., 1978 (Cassette 18, Cd ohaloh020171b1p1 / ohaloh020171b1p2, Cd ohaloh020172b1p3 / ohaloh020172b1p4, Cd ohaloh020173p1 / ohaloh020173p2, Cd OH-02-191, OH-02-192)
- Martin Birnbaum, Feb 5, 1978 (Cassette 18, Cd Access OH-02-192, Cd ohaloh020173p1, ohaloh020173p2)
- Martin Birnbaum Description: Yiddish literary work; Moshe Nadir; Jewish popular culture., 1983 (Cassette 19, Cd ohaloh020174p1 / ohaloh020174p2, Cd Access OH-02-194)
- Violet Wainio Bjong, Jul 7, 1984 (Cassette 265, Box 1, Cd Bjong 1, Cd ohaloh0200121p1 / ohaloh0200121p2)
  Activities of father and mother, Finnish-American radical leaders, 1920s-1930s; activities in Fitchburg, Mass., 1930s; work on Left-oriented daily, Fitchburg; life in Brooklyn cooperative housing; reflections.
- Fred Blair, Jul 26, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Blair 1, Cd access OH-02-007, Cassette 20, Cd ohaloh020007p1 / ohaloh020007p2)
  Role of ethnicity in Communist Party of Wisconsin, 1930s-40s; support of Left from Polish sector dating back to 1880, support of other Slav groups from 1910s; role of Meta Berger in Wisconsin Party and Blair's ascendency to state leadership; unemployment demonstration in Milwaukee and influence on students in Madison, University of Wisconsin; increase of District membership with addition of northern Wisconsin; character of northern Wisconsin rural Communists; exodus of rural Communists from state, 1940s-50s; McCarthyism and decline of Communist support.
- Norman Bloomfield, May 7, 1983 (Cassette 21, Box 1, Cd ohaloh020175p1 / ohaloh020175p2, Cd Access OH-02-195)
  Young People's Socialist League, 1930s; Trotskyism; Berkeley campus; work in shipyards.
- Grace Lee Boggs, Mar 28, 1983 (Cassette 22, Cd Access OH-02-008, Cd ohaloh02008p1 / ohaloh020008p2, Box 1, Cd G. Boggs 1)
  Asian-American family background in Providence, R.I.; education and involvement in radical politics in New York, late 1930s; Workers Party and Johnson-Forest tendency, 1940s; Correspondence, Detroit, 1950s; involvement in the black movement with her husband, James Boggs; comments on C.L.R. James.
- James Boggs, Mar 29, 1983 (Cassette 23, Cd OH-02-009 / OH-02-010, Cd ohaloh020009b1p1 / ohaloh020009b1p2 / ohaloh020010b1p3, Box 1, Cd J. Boggs 1-2)
  Youth in South; factory life in Detroit, 1930s-40s; Johnson-Forest Tendency; activities in 1960s-70s.
- Paul Booth Description>: Students for a Democratic Society, 1960s, Oct 1969 (Cassette Index only)
- Frank Bohn, Mar 1, 1958 (Cd access OH-02-011, Cd ohaloh020011p1, Box 1, Cd Bohn 1, Cassette 24)
  Memories of Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Thomas Hagerty, the Catholic church, Socialist Labor Party.
- Fannie Borun, Jan 6, 1981 (Box 1, Cassette 25, Cd Borun 1, Cd Access OH-02-196, Cd ohaloh020176p1 / ohaloh020176p1)
  Political struggles within the International Ladies Garment Workers Union, 1920s; experiences on trips in the Soviet Union, 1930s; women and the Communist Party.
  Interview by Bea Lemisch.
- Judy Boudon, Feb 8, 1982 (Box 1, Cd Boudon 1-2, Cassette 26 A-B, Cassette 26, Cd Access OH-02-012 / OH-02-013, Cd ohaloh020012p1, Cd ohaloh020013p1 / ohaloh020013p2)
  Immigration from Panama; Spanish immigrant community in New York, 1930s; office and factory work; America Labor Party; Communist Party, and women in the CP.
  Interview by Ruth F. Prago.
  Electronic transcript and Index available
- Thomas Brandon, Nov 4, 1976 (Cd Access OH-02-197, OH-02-198, Cassette 27, Cd ohaloh020177p1 / ohaloh020177p2, Box 1, Cd Brandon 1-2)
  Workers' Newsreel and Film and Photo League, early 1930s.
  Interview by Russell Campbell.
- Jeremy Brecker, Mar 31, 1970 (Box 1, Cd Brecker 1, Cassette 28)
  no access cassettes / Masters only
  Students for a Democratic Society, 1962-65.
  Interview by Kirkpatrick Sale.
- George Breitman, Jan 4, 1971 (Box 1, Cd Breitman 1-3, Cassette 29, Cd Access OH-02-014 / OH-02-015 / OH-02-016, Cd ohaloh020014b1p1 / ohaloh020014b1p2, Cd ohaloh020015b1p3 / ohaloh020015b1p4, Cd ohaloh020016b1p5, Cassette 29 A-C)
  Unemployed organizations in New Jersey; Socialist Workers Party, 1938-54.
- Harry Brier, Aug 26, 1983 (Box 1, Cd Brier 1, Cd ohaloh020017, Cd Aceess OH-02-017, Cassette 30)
  East End of London, 1920s-30s; Jewish character of Communist support; anti-fascist activities in London, 1920-30s; immigration to Los Angeles and union activities, 1940s-present.
- Miriam Braverman, Nov 8, 1984 (Cassette 364)